時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
바벨 13에 잠입한 무사시 일행은 한조의 함정에 걸려 잡히고 말았다.
Musashi and others managed to sneak into Babel 13, but they were captured with Hanzō's trap.
노부나가는 센히메를 죽여도 괜찮으니 잡아 오라는 명령을 내린다.
Nobunaga orders Dokuganryu to capture Senhime, allowing to kill her.
위태로운 센히메. 그러나 우시와카, 벤케이, 제니가탄의 활약으로 궁지에서 벗어난다.
Senhime's in crisis. But thanks to Ushiwaka, Benkei, and Zenigatan, they escape from crisis.
에도토피아
대위기이오
Edotopia
in Big Crisis
ドクガンリュウ、バベル13の自爆スイッチを入れいれろ！
バベル13をお捨てになるつもりですか。
このようなものはもう必要ないわ。
これからは江戸城がわしの城だ。
エドトピアに総攻撃をかける！
は！
自爆スイッチ、作動します。
노부나가 님.
Mr. Nobunaga.
음, 바벨 13을 버린 바, 이렇게 되었으니...
Well, now we've left Babel 13, we have only one choice.
우리 총력으로 이에야스와 국왕을 쏜다.
We will get Ieyasu and the king with all our forces.
예.
Yes.
원래대로라면 자연히 내 손에 지팡구국이 들어올 예정이었지만 이렇게 되었으니 어쩔 수 없다.
Jipangu State should have been in my hands by now, but since this happened, we will have to do this.
지팡구국의 수도 에도토피아를 한번에 쳐부순다!
We will destroy Edotopia, the capital of Jipangu State!
예!
Yessir!
진로, 에도토피아로!
Head to Edotopia!
예!
Yessir!
에, 제군, 보아하니 노부나가가 탄 메가톤성은 이대로 에도토피아를 목적지로 날아갔다.
Err, everyone, Nobunaga is riding on Megaton Castle and heading to Edotopia right away.
에도토피아로?
To Edotopia!?
잠깐만. 여기엔 나에 코지로에...
Wait-dasu. I'm here, Kojirō's here, ...
모두가 여기에 있다는 것은...
Everyone's here, and that means...
에도토피아는 비어 있구나.
Edotopia is empty.
이거 끔찍하군!
This is bad!
바로 쫓소!
We'll chase immediately-dasu!
이게 무슨 짓이오!
What was that for-dasu!?
바보야! 상대는 하늘을 날고 있어! 뛰어서 쫓을 수 있을 리가 없잖아!
You moron! The opponent is flying! There's no way possible that we can chase them by running!
그건 그렇지만, 안 가면 안 되오!
That's true-dasu, but we have to go-dasu!
기분 나쁜 할배이오.
What an eerie geezer-dasu.
이야, 이럴 거라 생각해서 따로 준비해둔 게 있다.
I thought this was going to happen, so I have something prepared.
따로 준비해둔 것?
Something?
뭐야뭐야, 그거, 어서 보여줘!
What is that? Show us!
보고 싶냐?
Wanna see?
보고 싶어, 보고 싶어, 보고 싶어!
I want to, I want to, I want to!
그럼 내게도 보여줄 거야?
Then will you show me, too?
아프겠다.
That must've been hurt.
이거야말로 정의의 대발명, 전기 터보 스크류다!
This is the great invention of justice: Electric Turbo Screw!
이거라면 수면을 아무 문제도 없이 달릴 수 있지.
With this, you can run on water surface without any problem.
그래도 이런 모습으로...
But, look at that...
그래도 저걸 붙일 탈것이라...
But, what vehicle can we put that on?
자!
Look!
역시 겐나이 씨이오!
Mr. Gennai, you're awesome-dasu!
정오에 파도를 빌려 파력을 쓰지 않고도 해면 위에서 미끄러지지도 않도록 머리 잘 굴려 뒀지.
I did my best to come out with something that will let you move without using the power of waves, when there isn't any.
음, 지팡구국 제일의 발명가만이 할 수 있는 것입니다.
Yes, that kind of job is only possible for the best inventor of Jipangu State.
옆의 하이레그도 그럴까나?
Is the high-leg girl next to you one, too?
잠깐, 겐나이 씨, 지금은 그런 소리를 할 때가 아니잖아?
Hey, Mr. Gennai, do you mind?
네, 네...
Yes, yes...
어쨌든, 지라이얀 기분 좋아 보이네.
Anyway, Jiraiyan looks happy.
가라가라!
Go, go!
쟤, 평화롭소.
He's so pecaeful-dasu.
그보다도, 궁지에 몰린 노부나가 놈들은 뭘 할지 모른다.
Anyway, we do not know what will that Nobunaga do, as he's now cornered.
한번에 승부를 내려고 하겠지요.
He'll try to finish this immediately.
에도토피아가 걱정되오.
I'm worried about Edotopia-dasu.
불타라, 타올라라, 불타버려라! 에도토피아를 불탄 벌판으로 만들어 버려라!
Burn, burn, and burn up! Make Edotopia into a burnt field!
노부나가 님. 그러나 그리하면 에도토피아는 폐허가 되고 맙니다.
Mr. Nobunaga. But that will make Edotopia into a ruins.
그랬다간 본전도 못 건지는 게...
That will leave you nothing.
음, 한조는 아직 모르는 듯 하구나.
It seems that you don't know yet, Hanzō.
예?
Yes?
내가 천하를 손에 잡으면 이에야스가 만든 것을 전부 내가 원하는 대로 다시 만들 것이다.
When I take the world in my hands, I will rebuild everything that Ieyasu made, in a way I like.
모두 내 원하는 대로다.
Everything will be as I desire.
이 에도토피아도 장엄한 아즈치 팔레스로 다시 짓겠다.
I will rebuild this Edotopia into the grand Azuchi Palace.
하잘것없는 인간은 처치하고 모든 것을 파괴해, 나를 위한 낙원을 만들 것이다.
I will get rid of all worthless humans, destroy everything, and build a paradise for me.
그걸 위해서도 오래된 것은 전부 부수겠다! 파괴하고, 파괴하고, 끝없이 파괴하는 것이다!
For that too, I will destroy everything that's old! Destroy, destroy, and destroy more!
그렇게 해야 새로운 질서가 태어날 수 있는 것이다!
That's how the new system borns!
내... 내 에도토피아가!
My... my Edotopia!
주베는! 주베는 어쨌나!
Jūbee! Where's Jūbee?
예, 아직 연락이 닿지 않습니다.
Yessir, he couldn't be reached yet.
노부나가 놈!
That Nobunaga bastard!
늦었소...
We're late-dasu...
살려줘!
Help me!
용서할 수 없어!
Unforgivable!
노부나가, 네이놈!
Nobunaga, you bastard!
지라이얀 님. 케로키치로 소화 활동에 참여해 주세요.
Mr. Jiraiyan, please put off fire with Kerokichi.
제니가탄 님, 우시와카 님, 벤케이 님도 부탁드립니다.
Mr. Zenigatan, Mr. Ushiwaka, and Mr. Benkei, please join.
예!
Yes!
센히메 님과 오츠루 씨는 아이들을!
Senhime and Ms. Otsuru will take care of the children!
네!
Got it!
-그럼...
-우리는...
-메가톤성을 막습니다.
-Then...
-we will...
-stop Megaton Castle.
저건 분명 합체성!
That must be Fusion Castle!
영주님! 저기에 주베 님하고 나머지가!
Lord! There's Mr. Jūbee and others!
오, 그런가!
Oh, is that so!?
메가톤성, 이자식! 무슨 짓이오!
Hey, Megaton Castle! What are you doing-dasu!?
끈질긴 놈들. 무사시 놈들을 먼저 처리해라!
How persistent of them! Get rid of Musashi bastards first!
무사시 얘들이라고 해도 어떻게 할 수 있는 상대가 아닌 건가...
Even for Musashi and others, are they too tough for them?
지팡구국 최고의 위기구나.
It's the biggest crisis ever of Jipangu State.
여긴 닛코. 노부나가에게 노려지는 국왕이 은둔 생활을 하고 있다.
This place is Nikko. The king is living a life in seclusion, to be out of reach of Nobunaga.
오, 마침 딱 좋구나.
This is just right.
떫은 감이구나, 이건.
This is an astringent persimmon...
국왕 전하!
Your Highness!
오, 쇼토쿠. 어디 갔다 왔나.
Oh, Shotoku. Where have you been?
네가 없어서 떫은 감을 먹고 말았잖냐.
Because you weren't here, I ended up eating an astringent persimmon.
감 따위 베어 먹고 있을 때가 아닙니다!
This is not a time to be eating some persimmons!
무슨 일이야?
What's wrong?
예, 정보에 따르면, 에도토피아가 노부나가에게 화공을 받고 있다고 합니다.
Per intelligence, Edotopia is being attacked by Nobunaga by fire.
뭐, 뭣이? 노부나가에게?
W- what? Nobunaga?
어찌하시겠습니까.
What should we do?
그렇구나. 알겠다.
I see. I get it.
국왕 전하, 어쩔 생각이십니까.
Your Highness, what are you going to do?
노부나가가 오는 거잖아? 달아나야 하는 게 뻔하지.
Isn't Nobunaga coming? Of course we have to run away.
국왕 전하! 그렇게 나약한 소리를 하시면 어찌합니까!
Your Highness! You cannot be feeble at a time like this!
그래도 말야... 난 노부나가가 싫어.
But, you know... I hate Nobunaga.
정보에 따르면 에도토피아는 분명 메가톤성에게 공격받고 있답니다.
According to what I've heard, Edotopia is being attacked by Megaton Castle.
하늘 나는 메가톤성?
You mean that flying Megaton Castle?
이제 슬슬 초공전을 쓸 때입니다.
(Chokuden: lit. Super Sky(Flying) Palace)
This is the time to use Chokuden.
초공전?
Chokuden?
예.
Yes.
만일의 경우, 어디에도 날아갈 수 있도록 준비된 초공전입니다.
This Chokuden is ready to fly to anywhere in times of need.
그러니까, 이대로 달아나는 게 낫지 않아?
Again, wouldn't it be better for us to run away on this?
지팡구국을 노부나가가 제패하면 어디까지든 따라 올 겁니다.
If Nobunaga takes control of Jipangu State, he will chase you to anywhere.
여기는 이에야스 님에게 가세해 노부나가를 쓰러트릴 수밖에.
We will have to join Mr. Ieyasu and take down Nobunaga.
그래도...
But...
그래도 할 때가 아닙니다.
No buts. There are no shortcuts.
다시 생각해 봐.
Please think again.
그럴 수는 없습니다.
I will not do that.
끈기를 갖고 덤벼야만 합니다.
We have to fight with all our guts.
지팡구국 존망의 위기입니다.
The whole Jipangu State is at stake.
나는 높은 게 싫어!
I hate high places!
참아 주십시오. 이건 시급한 일입니다. 무엇보다도, 센히메 님도 말려들어 계십니다.
Please bear with it. This is an urgent matter. Most of all, Senhime is involved in this.
뭣이? 센히메가?
What? Senhime?
에도토피아는 이대로 완전히 불타오르고 마는가. 국왕이 탄 초공전은 어떤 활약을 할 것인가.
Will Edotopia end up being completely burnt like this? What will Chokuden do, with the Highness on board?
질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
이쪽이다! 다들 서두르지 마라! 괜찮다!
This way! Nobody panic! It'll be alright!
이래서는 사막에 물 퍼붓는 것하고 다를 게 없어.
This is no different from pouring water on some desert.
으악! 살려주시오!
Wah! Help us-dasu!
왜 그러냐, 무사시!
What's wrong, Musashi?
무사시!
Musashi!
오센짱! 여긴 위험하오! 어서 도망치시오!
Osenchan! It's dangerous here-dasu! Run away fast-dasu!
용서하지 말고 끝장을 내라!
Do not forgive them; finish them!
어! 막장이오!
End of the road-dasu!
드디어 여기까진가.
Is this our end?
뭐, 뭐야, 저건!?
W- what's that!?
기회다! 이 틈에!
Our chance! Now!
좋소!
Right!
뭔지는 모르겠지만 아군인 듯 하오!
I'm not sure, but that seems to be a friendly force-dasu!
가 보자.
Let's go.
무사시 님! 무사해서 다행이다.
Mr. Musashi! It's good to have you safe.
쇼토쿠 씨! 이것의 주인은 쇼토쿠 씨이오?
Mr. Shotoku! Were you the owner of this-dasu?
이건 초공전이라고 하는 무적의 배다.
This is an invincible ship named Chokuden.
초공전.
Chokuden.
그렇지!
Indeed!
센히메. 안녕하세요.
Senhime, good afternoon.
구, 국왕 전하!
Y- your Highness!
이 탈것으로 국왕 전하께서 직접 노부나가의 메가톤성에 공격하셨나요?
Did you attack Nobunaga's Megaton Castle by yourself, using this thing?
응, 그래.
Yes, you're right.
멋져!
Awesome!
세, 센히메 님...
S- Senhime...
이거라면 마침 딱 좋소. 내가 이걸로 메가톤성에 쳐들어가겠소!
That will just do-dasu. I'll invade into Megaton Castle using that-dasu!
무사시! 네가 간다면 나도 간다!
Musashi! If you're going, then me too!
그럼 저도!
I'll join!
잠깐만! 이건 국왕 전하의 탈것이야!
Wait! The Highness owns this!
아니아니, 마음에 드셨다면 타세요. 괜찮지, 쇼토쿠?
No, no, if you like it, then please get in. Can they, Shotoku?
아, 예. 국왕 전하가 그리 생각하신다면.
Er, yes, if your Highness thinks so.
마음 넓으신 분!
What a big-hearted man!
아니아니, 만약 좋다면 이걸 여러분에게 진정해 드리겠습니다.
No, no, if you'd like, I'll present this to all of you.
국왕 전하!
Your Highness!
-이야, 도량이 커!
-상관 없다, 상관 없어!
-How generous!
-Don't worry, don't worry!
그럼 어서!
Then, let's hurry!
조심해.
Be careful.
그 마음 씀씀이도 멋져!
That mindset is also awesome!
어서 오시오, 코지로!
Come here, Kojirō!
으, 응...
Y- yeah...
좋소, 노부나가 놈들이 원하는 대로 날뛰는 건 이제 끝이오!
Alright! Those Nobunaga bastards won't be doing whatever they want anymore-dasu!
자, 출격!
Let's go!
조심해!
Be careful!
부탁한다, 무사시!
It's up to you, Musashi!
젠장, 노부나가! 덤벼 봐라! 이 코지로가 상대해 주겠다!
Nobunaga, you bastard! Come out! I, Kojirō, will face you!
코지로, 꽤나 거칠어졌소.
Kojirō seems to be in a pretty bad temper-dasu.
신경 쓰지 마세요.
Don't worry about that.
왔겠다, 노부나가! 무사시! 멍하니 있지 말고 기습 공격이다!
You're finally here, Nobunaga! Don't be dazed and do a surprise attack!
아, 알겠소!
G- got it-dasu!
좋아, 한방에 때려부숴라!
Alright, take them down with a single blow!
코지로, 잘 피하시오!
Kojirō! Evade well-dasu!
바보야, 너야말로 제대로 응전해라!
You fool! You fight back first!
쫓아라, 쫒아! 몰아넣어라! 질질 끌다 죽여라!
Chase them, get them! Corner them! Torture them to death!
코지로 님. 이대로는 당하는 것도 시간의 문제입니다. 일단 저기에.
Mr. Kojirō, it's only a matter of time before they get us. Go to there first.
좋습니다.
Roger.
우와, 솜사탕, 솜사탕이오!
Yay! Cotton candies! Cotton candies-dasu!
아니잖아!
You're wrong!
젠장. 어디로 사라졌나.
Damn. Where did they disappear to?
노부나가 님. 깊이 쫓아 들어가는 건 위험합니다.
Lord Nobunaga. It is dangerous to chase them too far.
뭐라?
What?
만약 제가 무사시라면, 여긴...
If I was Musashi, then I'd...
좋소, 코지로! 속도를 낮추시오!
Now, Kojirō! Decelerate-dasu!
뭔 소리냐! 여긴 어서 달아나야!
What are you saying!? We have to get out of here!
아니, 여기선 한번에 쳐들어가오!
No, we'll enter at once!
뭐!?
What!?
결전이오. 저 메가톤성의 뒤로 돌아 들어가 한번에 돌입이오!
It's time for a decisive match-dasu. We'll go round and cut into the back of Megaton Castle at once-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
무사시 님!
Mr. Musashi!
도쿠간류. 네 말, 잘 들었다.
Dokuganryu, I will agree to your opinion.
반드시 무사시를 쓰러트려라!
Take down Musashi no matter what!
예!
Yessir!
좋아! 감속!
Alright! Slowing down!
그래, 지금이다!
Now's our chance!
무사시! 이야기가 다르잖아!
Musashi! You're wrong!
이렇게 되어도 뒤로 못 달아나오!
Even then, we can't go back-dasu!
바, 바보야!
Y- you fool!
무사시! 재앙 속에 뛰어드는 단고 고맹이!
Musashi! You're a dango brat dashing to your doom!
아무도 없습니다!
Nobody's on board!
찾아라! 철저히 찾아라!
Find them! Find them exhaustively!
좋아! 초공전은 자동 조종으로 돌아가게 해 뒀다.
Alright! I set Chokuden to go back by itself.
적은 노부나가 단 하나!
We have only one enemy: Nobunaga!
에도토피아는 우리가 지킨다.
We will protect Edotopia.
무사시 님. 코지로 님. 부디 조심하시길.
Mr. Musashi. Mr. Kojirō. Please be careful.
예.
Got it.
있다! 코지로가 있다!
He's there! Kojirō's there!
에잇! 방해 마라!
Get out of my way!
노부나가! 나와라!
Nobunaga! Come out!
나오시오, 노부나가!
Come out, Nobunaga!
누구이오!
Who's that!?
네놈은 도쿠간류!
You must be Dokuganryu!
무사시. 끝장을 낼 때가 온 것 같구나. 기다리고 있었다.
Musashi. It seems that the time to settle this has came. I was waiting for you.
노부나가는 어디 있소!
Where's Nobunaga-dasu!?
네놈에게 알려줄 생각은 없다!
I do not intend to tell you!
젠장! 그렇다면!
Damn! If then!
카라쿠리 변화!
Karakuri Shift!
겐토쿠 아머!
Gentoku Armor!
쌍두의 용이여, 나와라!
Show yourself, Double-Headed Dragon!
무사시! 각오해라!
Musashi! Prepare yourself!
네이놈!
You bastard!
이자식! 용서할 수 없다!
How dare you! Unforgivable!
제정신이 아니군, 도쿠간류!
You're out of your mind, Dokuganryu!
이천일류!
Niten'ichiryū!
쌍룡검!
Double Dragon Sword!
무, 무념이다.
H- how regretful.
노부나가!
Nobunaga!
뭐라? 무사시 놈들이?
What? Musashi bastards!?
한조! 부하를 모아서 맞서라!
Hanzō! Gather subordinates and stop them!
예!
Yessir!
에도토피아가 타는 걸 가만히 보고 있어야 한다니!
I can't stand just watching Edotopia being burnt up!
겐나이 씨! 뭔가 좋은 방법 없어요?
Mr. Gennai! Is there anything we can do?
이건 어떻게 될지도 몰라.
Maybe something might be possible.
정말!?
Really!?
무사시 일행은 과연 불타오르고 있는 에도토피아를 구하는 데 성공할 것인가?
Will Musashi and others managed to rescue Edotopia, which is being completely burnt?
그리고 무사시와 노부나가의 최후의 결전은 어찌?
And how will the last battle between Musashi and Nobunaga end?
이야기는 슬슬 종국에 치닫는다.
The story is approaching the finale.
파란만장한 다음 이야기를 기다려라!
Wait for the turbulent next story!
싸우고 맞았어
I fought and I got beaten
코피 쓩이야 랑데부
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
나도 지지 않으려 한발!
I can't lose, so take my blow!
핀치 펀치로 대역전
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
다음 시간 즐거운
Next is delightful lunchtime
급식일 텐데
But it's not delightful today
선생님의 벼락이
The thunder of my teacher
나한테만 떨어져 왔어
only hit me and nobody else
사정을 말해도
I tried to explain
들어주지 않는 채
But he won't listen
어떻게 해도 역시
Now whatever I do
눈물이 나오고 말아
I end up crying
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
왠지 안타까워
you'll feel downhearted
에도토피아를 구하기 위해 국왕 전하는 삼종의 신기 중 하나, 성검을 노부나가에 넘기기로 결정하였소.
To save Edotopia, the Highness decided to hand over
one of the Three Sacred Treasures, to Nobunaga-dasu.
과연 지팡구는 악인의 손에 들어가는 것일지는 모르오.
Will Jipangu end up falling over to the hands of bad guy-dasu?
그러나 천하를 노리는 한조는 노부나가를 죽이고 마오!
But, looking for the ruling power, Hanzō kills Nobunaga-dasu!
정말 나쁜 건 역시 한조였소!
The one who's truly bad really is Hanzō-dasu!
다음 이야기! 꽃의 무사시 악을 베오
Next story! Flowering Musashi Cuts the Evil
질퐁노도의 에도토피아오!
It's the stormy Edotopia-dasu!
다음 이야기
꽃의 무사시
악을 베오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Flowering Musashi
Cuts the Evil
Look forwards for it!